What's up preppies?
Hello everyone!
Welcome back to the next lesson on IELTS Writing Tasks 2.
To warm up, why don't we play a small game?
I have two pictures here showing two aspects of the internet.
Can you help me guess what they are?
You'll have 10 seconds.
Have you guessed it yet?
The pictures show two aspects of the internet,
the advantages and disadvantages.
We can see that the advantages include entertainment
and people's connection, while the disadvantages are risks,
personal information leaks, self-isolation from the real world, and so on.
In today's lesson, we'll learn about advantages and
disadvantages questions in IELTS Writing Tasks 2 and
focus on the first criterion, which is TR, Task Response.
Our lesson is divided into two parts.
Part 1, Task Analysis and Brainstorming, and Part 2, Sample Introduction and Improvements.
To achieve three goals.
To understand how to analyze advantage and disadvantage questions.
To apply the mind-mapping technique to brainstorm
ideas for advantage and disadvantage questions.
To understand how to make an outline for
an advantage-disadvantage essay at Band 6 in Task Response.
Let's move on to the first part.
Advantages and Disadvantages For this question type,
we will be asked to write about the advantages
and disadvantages of a particular subject or phenomenon
and decide whether the advantages are stronger than the disadvantages or not.
Some common questions are.
What are the advantages and disadvantages of?
Do you think the advantages outweigh the disadvantages?
Discuss the advantages and disadvantages and give your opinion.
Do you think this is a positive or negative development?
The third question seems a bit different from the previous two, doesn't it?
However, basically they all ask about the advantages and disadvantages.
If a development has more advantages than disadvantages, it's a positive development.
On the other hand, if it has more
disadvantages than advantages, it's a negative development.
So, we still need to do two tasks.
Write about both the advantages and disadvantages of
that development and decide whether the advantages of
that development are stronger than the disadvantages.
From there, we can figure out if it's
a positive or a negative development.
So, let's move on to task analysis.
After reading a question, we always start with task analysis.
At this step, what do we need to analyze and find out?
Let's take three seconds to remember.
That's right, we have to find topic words,
microtopic words, and instruction words.
I have a small challenge for you.
You have 20 seconds to underline and identify
the topic words, microtopic words, and instruction words in the following question.
Your time starts now.
All right, now let's see if your answers are correct.
In this question, we have topic words,
the phrases that present the main subject we need to discuss.
Here they are.
Digital advancements and working from home.
But do we write about all aspects of
digital advancements, like how computers are built or specific software?
Certainly not.
So, we need to rely on the micro topic words
to see exactly which aspect we need to write about.
The microtopic words here are become a more and more popular option.
This means we should focus on the trend,
the fact that technology has made remote work
a widespread choice for many people.
We are analyzing this specific development, the shift in popularity.
Finally, to understand what we are required to
do with this topic, let's look at the instruction words.
Do the advantages of this development outweigh the disadvantages?
Based on these words, what do they tell us to do?
You need to weigh the pros against the cons.
Please answer the following interactive question to confirm you understand the task.
Have you got the correct answer?
Remember, with the question, do the advantages of
this development outweigh the disadvantages?
We need to write about both the advantages
and disadvantages of the given topic and give
personal opinions by saying if the advantages are
stronger than the disadvantages.
Now, let's brainstorm some ideas for this question.
Instead of using the listing technique like in
the previous lesson, why don't we use the mind mapping technique today?
Now, I have the following mind map with
the topic, working from home using modern technology,
and two aspects we need to discuss corresponding
to the two main branches, advantages and disadvantages.
So, what are the advantages and disadvantages of
using modern technology to work from home?
You can pause the video for three minutes
to fill in the ideas for each branch on this mind map.
If you have additional explanations, examples, or elaborations,
you can draw smaller branches from the main ideas.
Remember to use short English phrases when noting down.
Alright, have you all finished?
Now, I'll show you the mind map that I prepared.
Firstly, on the advantages branch, I have ideas as follow.
Firstly, one advantage of using technology to work
from home is flexibility because we can work anywhere.
This advantage was clearly shown during the COVID
period when we had to follow travel restrictions
and many areas were under lockdown.
Secondly, another advantage is time and money saving
because employees won't have to spend time commuting
or spend money on transportation.
Thirdly, work productivity will also increase due to
less distractions and a comfortable working space.
Fourthly, there'll be a broader talent pool and
we can hire skilled individuals from anywhere without being limited by location.
On the disadvantages branch, I have the following ideas.
Firstly, less effective communication.
For example, co-workers may misunderstand emails of
other people leading to project delays.
Secondly, employees may easily experience poor work-life
balance as they work too much and forget
about their personal lives.
Thirdly, there is technology dependency.
It's noticeable that without technology, no tasks can be completed.
For example, during a power cut, employees are unable to work.
After discussing the advantages and disadvantages, you have
one more task to do, which is to
give your own opinion by saying if the
advantages are stronger than the disadvantages.
Based on the brainstormed ideas, here's a tip to help you answer this question.
If you have more ideas on the advantages branch,
you should choose advantages outweigh the disadvantages and vice versa.
Similar to the previous lesson, for the TR criterion, I'd like to begin with a big
question for you and that is, has this essay addressed the main parts of the question?
Now we have a sample essay for the question in part one as follows.
And this is the outline for the sample.
Now it's time for you to answer the question at the beginning.
Has this essay addressed the main parts of the question?
We can see that in the thesis statement,
the writer clearly stated his or her opinion
that the advantages to working from home are
stronger than the disadvantages.
It seems like the essay has addressed the question.
But let me tell you this.
This essay only got 5.0 for the task response criterion.
Why?
In the next part, based on this sample,
let's explore the reasons why this essay only
scored 5.0 and figure out how to
achieve band 6.0 plus for the task
response criterion in writing task two.
Firstly, let's take a look at the format of this essay.
In the previous lesson, we learned that to
achieve band 6.0 plus for task response,
the essay format needs to follow specific standards.
Now let's choose which standards they are.
An appropriate format at band 6.0 for task response includes
A. Introduction and conclusion
B. Three parts introduction, body and conclusion
C. The essay should be at least 200 words long
D. The essay should be at most 250 words long
or E. The essay should be at least 250 words long
The correct answers are B and E.
So considering these two aspects, this essay has a good structure and length.
A. Introduction For the advantages and disadvantages essays, to
write an introduction that achieves a band 6 .0 plus for task response, we need to do two things.
General statement introduced by paraphrasing that
The subject topic, phenomenon mentioned in the question has both
the advantages and disadvantages.
Thesis statement.
State the writer's opinion on whether the advantages
of this subject, topic or phenomenon  are stronger than the disadvantages.
Now you have one minute to consider if
this introduction has met these requirements.
Let's take a look at the answer.
In the general statement, the writer introduced by
paraphrasing that using modern technology to work from home
has provided people with many benefits as well as drawbacks.
Thesis statement.
The writer gave his or her opinion on this phenomenon.
From my viewpoint, the advantages outweigh the disadvantages.
We can see that this is a well -written introduction, so there's nothing to improve yet.
You can learn from it.
For the body, to ensure we achieve band 6
for task response, we follow two steps.
Step 1.
Identify which side is more supported and put it in body 2.
Our thesis supports advantages, so we must move the advantages paragraph to the end.
Let's swap them.
Step 2.
Ensure there is a clear topic sentence.
Looking at our new body 2, it jumps straight into details.
We must add a clear opening sentence to announce the main idea.
Advantages of using modern technology to work from home.
Now look closely at the ideas in this paragraph.
Can you spot one unrelated idea?
We can see that advantage 1, working during
the pandemic, is directly related.
However, look at advantage 2.
Is finding a job online the same as working from home?
Of course not.
This point is about searching for jobs,
not the act of working remotely.
Therefore, it is irrelevant.
Let's replace it with a relevant idea.
Saving money and time, as workers don't have to commute.
Similar to the previous paragraph, body 1, disadvantages,
also contains an unrelated explanation.
Can you spot it?
It is disadvantage 2, unofficial news.
Why?
Because unofficial news is a general disadvantage of the internet.
It does not focus on the specific drawback of working from home.
Therefore, it is off topic.
Here is my suggestion to fix it.
Poor work-life balance.
This happens when workers overwork because they lack clear boundaries.
Put them all together and here is the complete improved outline for our essay.
Those are two steps to achieve band 6.0+ for TR in the body.
Step 1: Identify which side is more supported: Advantage or Disadvantage, then write it in body 2.
Step 2: Choose the appropriate explanations and examples from the mind map based on
the main idea of each paragraph.
Looking at the sample outline, I want you
to note, do not just list the advantages
and disadvantages without explaining them.
Once you've completed the mind map, you may have a lot of ideas.
However, for each body paragraph, we should only
choose two ideas to develop in your essay.
To get a band 6.0 for conclusion,
for this question type, you need to do two things.
Summarize all ideas in the body.
With this type, you often need to restate
that the given topic has both the advantages and disadvantages.
Restate the writer's opinion on whether the advantages or the disadvantages are stronger.
Let's take a look at the conclusion of the sample.
To sum up, I reckon that technology has both benefits and drawbacks.
However, in my opinion, the advantages considerably outweigh the disadvantages.
Wait a minute.
There seems to be something wrong.
Do you notice the big mistake here?
It's the part technology has both benefits and drawbacks.
We're not talking about technology in general in this essay.
It should be using modern technology to
work remotely has both benefits and drawbacks.
And with this sentence, we could also summarize
the ideas discussed in the essay.
Next, has the writer restored his or her opinion yet?
Yes, he or she has.
We can see that in the sentence, in my opinion, the advantages considerably outweigh the disadvantages.
And now, let's wrap up today's lesson.
So, today we've learned how to improve the
TR criterion to band 6 for the advantages
and disadvantages essay based on the outline of it.
Firstly, we practiced task analysis.
Then, we applied the mind mapping technique to generate ideas.
Now, it's time for a quick exercise to
check if you've understood the main content of today's lesson.
Have you got the correct answer?
If you have, then congratulations.
You've understood this lesson.
And now, I'll see you in the next video.
See ya.